A Guide to the Francis O. Holmes papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA129
Rockefeller Archive Center
Francis O. Holmes papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1924-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
Holmes, Francis O. (Francis Oliver)
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA129
9.24 Cubic Feet 21 document boxes and dissertation.
Biographical/Historical note
Francis Oliver Holmes (1899-1990), phytopathologist. Born in Cambridge, Massachusetts on 26 November 1899 to Fannie Elizabeth Greenleaf Holmes and Frank William Holmes. Raised in Cambridge, Holmes graduated from Rindge Technical High School in 1916 and from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in June 1921 as one of their few graduates in biological sciences. Holmes pursued graduate work at Johns Hopkins University. There he met his future wife, L. Ruth Deem (1898-1982). They were married in 1924 and their one son, Francis William Holmes, was born in 1929.
Having studied under Robert W. Hegner at Johns Hopkins, Holmes was awarded a doctorate in science in 1924 based on his research thesis, "Herpetomonad Flagellates in Milkweed in the United States." The previous year, Holmes accepted the position of protozoologist at the Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research in Yonkers, NY. At the Institute, he worked in close association with Dr. Louis Otto Kunkel who was studying yellows viruses.
In 1932, when Dr. Kunkel was asked to develop a plant virology laboratory for the new Plant and Animal Pathology Department of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, he brought Holmes with him to Princeton, NJ. Holmes remained at the Rockefeller until his retirement in 1965.
During his career, Holmes was noted for his early discovery (1929) of a way to determine the relative concentration of plant virus particles, known as "local lesion assays." He was world-renowned for his long advocacy of the use of Latin binomials to name viruses, culminating in two editions of his book, Handbook of Phytopathogenic Viruses in 1939. This volume was expanded in 1948 under the title, The Filterable Viruses to include non-phytopathogenic viruses. Dr. Holmes developed tobacco-mosaic-virus disease resistant varieties in several crops, including tobacco, tomatoes, and sweet peppers. He served as an officer in the Northeast Division of the American Phytopathological Society. Shortly after his retirement, Holmes was the first recipient of the society's highest honor, the Ruth Allen Award. During his retirement years, Dr. Holmes taught virology for one year at the University of New Hampshire and one year at the University of Illinois.
In his sixty years of scientific research, Dr. Holmes listed 181 publications. Of these, sixty-one were published in the journal, Phytopathology, mostly before his retirement, and 49 more were published in Gleanings in Bee Culture, mostly after his retirement. The remaining 71 are found in 36 other journals or books.
During 1944, 1946, 1948, 1958, and 1959, Holmes and his wife were guests of the Puerto Rico Agricultural Experiment Station in Rio Pedras where he studied the papaya "bunchy-top" disease. In 1961-1962, while a consultant in virology for the United Nations Food and Agricultural Organization, Holmes went to the Guinobatan Agricultural Experiment Station in the Philippine Republic. Here he discovered that the fatal "cadang-cadang" disease of coconut palms did not occur wherever the trees were kept in weed-free surroundings. Thus insect vectors could be suppressed by eliminating certain environmental factors. Also under the auspices of the FAO, Holmes investigated related diseases at an Experiment Station in Kerala Province in southwestern India.
In his retirement years, Dr. Holmes lived in Henniker, New Hampshire, raising bees and studying the taxonomy of willows (Salix). Having first raised bees as a hobby while in New Jersey, once retired, Holmes published many articles about honey, bee life patterns, and nectar secretion of their food plants. Willow pollen is the earliest spring source of food for many bee colonies. Holmes gathered more than one hundred species of Salix on his farm and often donated to botanical gardens the species that they lacked.
Francis Oliver Holmes was struck by a vehicle while walking near his home in Henniker the evening of 12 October 1990, and died on the way to the hospital. He had lived 90 years and 10 1/2 months and is buried with his wife, Ruth, in the Henniker Cemetery.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 H735
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Related Materials
Twelve additional storage cartons of Holmes material exist (Boxes 7-18) which were received by RAC post-1988. All additional materials are closed to scholarly research pending further processing.
See FA803 Francis O. Holmes papers, Rockefeller University Faculty (Ingested by RAC post-1988).
Plant diseases; Plant viruses; Agriculture; Biology -- Research; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Life sciences; Diseases; Holmes, Francis O. (Francis Oliver); Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Correspondence, 1924-1979; 1; 8.4 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists primarily of correspondence, also includes some memoranda and reports.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Ab-Ad (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - D.V.W. Abeygunawardena, 1963
    - Jose Adsuar, 1945-1974
  - Ag-Ale (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Julian A. Agati, 1962-1965
    - George N. Agrios, 1971
    - G.C. Ainsworth, 1943 1949
    - Khursheed Akbar, 1952
    - E.G. Albritton, 1950 1952
    - Leonard J. Alexander, 1950 1953
  - Ali-American Men (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mohammed A. Ali, 1953
    - H.A. Allard, 1938
    - Peter H. Allen, 1969
    - L.A. Alvarez Garcia, 1945 1953 1955
    - American Bible Society, 1971
    - American Book Center for War Devastated Libraries, Inc., 1947
    - American Men of Science, 1946
  - American Phytopathological Society, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Phytopathological Society, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American R-And (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American Rose Magazine, 1960
    - American Society of Agronomy, 1954
    - Chris W. Anderson, 1950-1951 1956 1958
    - E.J. Anderson, 1953
    - Edgar Anderson, 1952
    - L.F. Anderson, 1953
    - P.J. Anderson, 1938
    - E. Emil Anderssen, 1938
    - C.H. Andrewes, 1949-1955 1958
    - D. Andrews - The Essex County [MA] Beekeepers Association, 1969-1971
  - Annual Reports - Holmes Laboratory, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ap-Az (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Apiculture, 1967 1972
    - George M. Armstrong, 1951
    - Arnold Arboretum, 1970 1972-1975 1977
    - A.V. Astrov, 1961
    - George S. Avery, 1956 1969-1970
    - Robert Aycock, 1953
    - Edward N. Azarowicz, 1955-1956
  - Bab-Ban (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - M.F. Babb, 1937
    - E.B. Babcock, 1938
    - Richard Bagnall, 1954
    - H. Gordon Bailey, 1951
    - L. Bailey, 1968
    - A.B. Baird, 1936
    - Julia Baldia, 1961
    - E.A. Ball, 1965
    - Ronald Bamford, 1943 1945 1948
    - Thomas L. Bancroft, 1929-1935
  - Fred A. Barkley, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fred A. Barkley, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fred A. Barkley, 1961-1965 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bar-Bav (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Milton Baron, 1970
    - Howard P. Barss, 1950
    - R.P. Bartholomew, 1941
    - Lela V. Barton, 1961
    - Engracio Basio, 1961
    - Conrad Bauer, 1925
    - W.E. Baulieu, 1951
    - K.V. Ahamed Bavappa, 1964
  - Baw-Bay (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - F.D. Bawden, 1941-1942 1944 1948-1950 1952
    - Martha B. Baylor, 1947 1949 1951
  - Beal-Bear (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - J.M. Beal, 1956
    - Helen Purdy Beale, 1941 1951-1952 1960 1963 1968
    - A.L. Beam, 1947
    - Firman E. Bear, 1939
  - J.H. Beaumont, 1946-1947 1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Beaur-Bei (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Henrique Beurepaire Aragao, 1932
    - J.B. Beckenbach, 1957
    - George G. Becker, 1950
    - Bee Culture Library, 1963-1965 1972
    - Bee Inspector, New Hampshire, 1971
    - Bee Research Association, 1965
    - Beekeeping Equipment, 1962
    - Walter G. Been, 1952
    - E.G. Beinhart, 1946 1950-1951
  - Gerd T.A. Benda, 1946 1947-1950 1953 1959 1963 1965 1970 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bende-Benj (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Harold H. Bender, 1939-1942
    - W.G. Benedict, 1954
    - Dante A. Benigno, 1961
    - Jaimes Benitez, 1944
    - C.R. Benjamin, 1961
  - C.W. Bennett, 1937 1939-1940 1942-1943 1945 1948-1949 1951 1953 1955 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Beq-Ber (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Joseph C. Bequaert, 1957 1971
    - A. Dorothy Bergner, 1943 1945
    - G H. Bergold, 1953 1955
    - G.H. Berkeley, 1934 1943-1944 1947 1949-1955
  - Bes-Bio (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Rupert J. Best, 1940-1941 1949-1950 1964
    - R.S. Bevan, 1947
    - K.S. Bhargava, 1949
    - Y.M. Bhatnagar, 1968
    - Avelino E. Bigornia, 1954 1960-1964
    - Biological Abstracts, 1947
    - Biological Handbooks, Office of, 1971
  - Julio Bird, 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Julio Bird, 1955-1962 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Agesilau A.B. Bitancourt, 1952 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Lindsay M. Black, 1935 1944-1945 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Lindsay M. Black, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lindsay M. Black, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Lindsay M. Black, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lindsay M. Black, 1958-1960 1963 1966-1967 1969 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Benjamin Blackburn, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Benjamin Blackburn, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Benjamin Blackburn, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Benjamin Blackburn, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Blak-Bost (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Albert F. Blakeslee, 1930-1931 1939 1942 1944 1948
    - Mildred Bleier, 1957
    - Earle C. Blodgett, 1941-1943
    - F.M. Blodgett, 1929
    - H. Loran Blood, 1943 1947
    - Hugh O. Bly, 1966
    - Reiner Bonde, 1953
    - James Bonner, 1957
    - L. Bos, 1960 1963
    - Boston Herald Traveler
  - Bot-Boy (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Botanical Congress, Tenth International, 1964
    - Donald C., Boughton, 1939 1945
    - Josy Bove n.d.
    - Orley G. Bowen, 1949-1950
    - Louis Bower, 1965
    - Gordon T. Bowles, 1949
    - J.S. Boyce, 1949
    - Q.C. Boyd, 1941 1948
    - Cynthia Boyer, 1956
    - John S. Boyle, 1952
  - Brab-Bras (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Stuart Brabant, 1950
    - W.H. Bragonier, 1955
    - Myron K. Brakke, 1965
    - Brand Peony Farms, 1959
    - J. Brandes, 1964
    - D.H. Brants, 1963
    - Edward F. Brarmann, Jr., 1959
    - Karl D. Brase, 1957
  - Brau-Bre (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Armin C. Braun, 1942 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1939 1943 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Robert S. Breed, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Brid-Brie (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - George H. Bridgmon, 1964-1965
    - Myrtle Brierley, 1966
    - Philip Brierley, 1945 1948-1949 1952 1955-1956 1959 1962-1964
  - Brin-Brit (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Richard F. Brinckerhoff, 1971-1972
    - R.A. Brink, 1934
    - Sarah E. Brittingham, 1960-1961 1963 1965-1966 1971
    - William H. Brittingham, 1959-1960 1952-1963
  - Magdalena L. Briones, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Magdalena L. Briones, 1964-1965 1969-1970 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bro-Bry (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - L. Broadbent, 1953-1954
    - Detlev W. Bronk, 1954 1956-1958 1960-1961 1964-1965
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, 1960
    - Bettie S. Brooks, 1947
    - Woodruff W. Bryne, 1958
  - R.E. Buchanan, 1939-1944 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - R.E. Buchanan, 1953 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - R.E. Buchanan, 1957-1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bun-Cali (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - H.J. Bunker, 1954
    - Bureau of Plant Industry, 1961
    - Bureau of Public Libraries, 1962
    - Burgess Publishing Company, 1940 1943-1945 1948
    - Jose S. Burgos, 1963
    - Arturo Burkart, 1938
    - James Burlew, 1956
    - F.M. Burnet, 1938-1939 1948 1955
    - W. Atlee Burpee Company, 1950-1951
    - A.B. Burrell, 1953 1955
    - Antonio D. Bustrillos, 1964
    - H. Buttenschoen, 1963
    - Colin Cadman, 1954-1955 1963-1964
    - John Caldwell, 1958
    - Carlos A. Calica, 1962 1964 1966
  - Cal-Cay (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Gary N. Calkins, 1925
    - Charles I. Campbell, 1957-1958
    - Anthony J. Campo, 1964-1965
    - Antonio Canova, 1957-1958
    - J.S. Canner and Co., 1954
    - Cesar Carrera, 1948
    - Eubanks Carsner, 1939 1941 1950-1952
    - Walter Carter, 1964-1965
    - Richard Cayouette, 1952
  - Chi-Clar (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - J.F.L. Childs, 1957
    - L.A. Chitwood, 1966
    - R.J. Chiu, 1967
    - J.S. Chohan, 1970-1971
    - Tyng-guang Chou, 1970
    - B. Choudhury, 1952 1963-1964
    - Emil Chroboczek, 1958
    - Charles Chupp, 1957
    - Ciba Foundation, 1964
    - H. Cirelli, 1937
    - Civil Service, 1948
    - Charles F. Clark, 1937
    - Edward J. Clark, 1951
    - William A. Clark, 1960-1961
    - Alfred E. Clarke, 1938
  - Clau-Cle (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Roy E. Clausen, 1928 1935-1937 1942 1950 1953
    - E.E. Clayton, 1938
    - F.F. Cleveland, 1957 1959
    - L.R. Cleveland, 1935
  - Phyllis E.M. Clinch, 1942 1948-1951 1953-1957 1960-1961 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Clint-Cog (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - G.P. Clinton, 1929 1937
    - Harold O. Clum, 1949 1951
    - George W. Cochran, 1948 1954 1956
    - H.L. Cochran, 1940
    - L.C. Cochran, 1953-1954 1962
    - J. Cochrane, 1950-1951
    - George Cockerham, 1952-1954
    - John M. Cogger, 1957
  - Cohen-Col (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mortimer Cohen, 1957-1960 1963 1968-1969
    - Sylvan I. Cohen, 1957
    - J.L. Collins, undated
  - Committee, 1940-1941; 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Committee - Standing [Committee on Virus Nomenclature of the American Phytopathological Society].
  - Committee, 1942-1943; 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Commo-Cong (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Barry Commoner, 1952-1957 1959
    - Arthur H. Compton, 1940
    - Karl T. Compton, 1936
    - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, 1949
    - Congrès Scientifique International du Tabac, 1955
  - Conn-Co (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - H.J. Conn, 1956
    - Robert Conover, 1948-1950 1952
  - Coo-Copy (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - A.A. Cook, 1957-1959 1963
    - Melville T. Cook, 1929 1931-1933 1937 1939-1940 1942 1944 1946 1948
    - George H. Coons, 1953 1971
    - Woodrow Coots, 1950
    - E.B. Copeland, 1954
    - Copyright Office, Library of Congress, 1948
  - M. Kenneth Corbett, 1955-1958 1961-1962; 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - M. Kenneth Corbett, 1962-1964 1969; 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Cord-Corn (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Aquilino S. Cordova, 1964
    - Coresta Information Bulletin, 1957
    - Cornell Library of Plant Pathology, undated
    - George W. Corner, 1957-1959
    - P. Cornuet, 1960
  - J.N. Corry, 1961; 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - J.N. Corry, 1961-1963; 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Corry-Cou (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Corry and Company, Ltd., 1951
    - W.W. Cort, 1943 1946 1948
    - A.S. Costa, 1939 1942-1943 1948-1949 1951-1952
    - Donald J. Cotter, 1958
    - Louisa Cottini, undated
    - Norris Cotton, 1971
    - Lewis W. Cottrell, 1932
    - Frank Cotui, 1961-1962
    - H.B. Couch, 1962
    - J.G. Coulson, 1929
    - John M. Coulter, 1927
  - Milton H. Cowan, 1948-1957 1961 1964 1966 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cow-Cra (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - R.S. Cowan, 1950
    - S.T. Cowan, 1954
    - Edmund V. Cowdry, 1925 1927-1928
    - Hiden T. Cox, 1962
    - Alden S. Crafts, 1936 1950
    - Charles F. Craig, 1926
    - J.C. Crawford, 1949
  - Cre-Crum (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - John L. Creech, 1951-1952 1954
    - Harriet B. Creighton, 1935 1937-1938
    - James M. Cribbins, 1947
    - William Crocker, 1925-1927 1929 1931 1935 1947
    - S.H. Crowdy, 1952
    - Neil Crowley, 1957-1958
    - Duane O. Crummett, 1944
  - Eugenio E. Cruz, 1955 1960-1961; 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Eugenio E. Cruz, 1961; 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cue-Cut (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Numeriano L. Cuevas, 1961
    - R.A. Cumber, 1955-1957
    - Cunnard White Star Line, 1939
    - Charles H. Cunningham, 1952 1956
    - Current Contents, 1959 1963
    - Laurence C. Curtis, 1941
    - Customs Service, Port of New York, 1962
    - Donald W. Cutler, 1926
  - Dai-Dan (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Robert H. Daines, 1955 1960 1962-1964
    - E.E. Dale, 1935 1937-1938
    - W.T. Dale, 1949 1951-1952
    - I.S. Danidagh, 1962
    - B.F. Dana, 1932 1938 1940
  - Dar-B.H. Davis (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - H.H. Darby, 1930
    - Lewis A. Darby, 1956 1964
    - George M. Darrow, 1952
    - Darwin Memorial Expedition, 1939
    - S.M. Das Gupta, 1950
    - Benjamin H. Davis, 1955-1959
  - E.W. Davis-Day (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Elmo W. Davis, 1938-1939 1964-1966
    - Glen N. Davis, 1939
    - R.E. Davis, 1976
    - Spencer H. Davis, 1949
    - T.A. Davis, 1963
    - J.A. Dawson, 1930
    - J.R. 0. Dawson, 1959 1966
    - M H. Dawson, 1939
    - Ray F. Dawson, 1945-1946 1949 1951
    - Max F. Day, 1958
    - Peter R. Day, 1966
  - Dea-Dew (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Horace S. Dean, 1952
    - J.L. Dean, 1971
    - J.A. de Bokx, 1964
    - Irving P. Delappe, 1950
    - Donald de Leon, 1964
    - Santiago Delgado Sanchez, 1960 1965
    - Milislav Demerec, 1946
    - Gordon P. de Wolf, Jr., 1971-1972
  - Den-Dey (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Robert K. Dennett, 1949-1952
    - R.W.G. Dennis, 1939
    - F.E. Denny, 1934
    - Department of Floriculture, Cornell University, 1956
    - Department of Water Supply, 1951
    - Paul R. Desjardins, 1955
    - Josue A. Deslandes, 1953
    - Alex Devet, 1970
    - M.J. Deyell
  - Dia-Doc (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Steven Diachun, 1950
    - Jaime R. Diaz, 1960-1961
    - James G. Dickson, 1952-1953
    - Sarah Dickson, 1950 1960
    - Alfred E. Dimond, 1950-1951
    - Director of Health Services, Mauritius, 1936
    - Division of Plant Exploration and Introduction, 1949
    - A.R. Dochez, 1940-1941 1944 1946-1948
  - Dod-Dol (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - B.O. Dodge, 1931 1940 1944
    - Robert Doerr, 1951
    - Desmond D. Dolan, 1954
    - Vincent Dole, 1964
  - S.P. Doolittle, 1934 1938 1941 1945 1947 1949 1952-1955 1957 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dou-Duff (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Archibald Douglas, Jr., 1952
    - H. Douwes, 1962
    - Dow Chemical Co., 1948
    - Draft Board, 1944
    - Carl J. Drake, 1930
    - John Drake, 1962
    - Byrley F. Driggers, 1953
    - D.M. Dring, 1961
    - Victor H. Dropkin, 1954
    - Pablo Duarte Roman, 1945
    - Ralph Dubler, 1947
    - René J. Dubos, 1958-1959
    - James E. Duffus, 1959
  - Dufr-Dw (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jean Dufrenoy, 1955-1958 1961
    - B.M. Duggar, 1933
    - C.W. Dunn, 1945?
    - Halbert L. Dunn, 1931
    - Duplicating Service - Rockefeller Institute, 1963
    - E. Melville Du Porte, 1925
    - Graham DuShane, 1957
    - John Duston, 1963
    - A.K. Dutt, 1958-1959
    - Vincent du Vigneaud, 1953
    - John D. Dwyer
  - Ea-Ela (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Earl Ferris Nursery Co., 1959
    - E.M. East, 1933 1937
    - Eastern Apicultural Society, 1968
    - Eastern Airlines, 1957
    - East Side Citizens Committee for Air Pollution Control, 1964
    - A. Eastwood, 1938
    - R.S. Edgar, 1958
    - L.V. Edgington, 1966
    - S. Edison, 1969
    - H.A. Edson
    - R. Egli, 1962
    - Merril Eisenbud, 1951
    - U.B.M. Ekanayake, 1964
    - Victoria M. Ela, 1962
  - Elf-Els (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - W.J. Elford, 1949
    - Harold Elishowitz, 1950
    - Roger C. Elliot, 1958 1960 1963-1965
    - F.C. Elsworth, 1944-1945
  - En-Eu (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Encyclopedia Enterprises, 1968
    - Encyclopedia of Science and Technology, 1968
    - W. Endemann, 1963
    - W.D. Enzie, 1945
    - C.O. Erlansen, 1950 1952
    - A.T. Erwin, 1933
    - Katherine Esau, 1933
    - Carlos Espina, 1932
    - Esso Standard Oil Company, 1951
    - Estación Experimental de Agricultura, 1938
    - Roman R. Estioko, 1960
    - Simeon A. Estocapio, 1961
    - European Tours Travel Service, 1964
  - Ev-Fank (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Alice C. Evans, 1940
    - A.S. Evans, 1957
    - A.J. Ewart, 1931
    - Thomas E. Ewert, 1971
    - H.C. Faan, 1950
    - Faculty Committee on Lectures, Rockefeller Institute, 1959
    - David E. Fairbrothers, 1957
    - T.G. Fajardo, 1934 1937 1940 1962
    - I. Fankuchen, 1941
  - Fant-Fed (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - H.B. Fantham, 1928-1929 1935
    - Donald G. Faris, 1965
    - Farm Journal, 1960 1966
    - C.L. Farrar, 1958
    - H.S. Fawcett, 1940-1941 1944
    - Federal Security Agency - NIH, 1953
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Closed.
  - Fel-Fern (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Hector Feliciano, 1944
    - E.L. Felix, 1947-1948
    - Frank J. Fenner, 1955
    - Nicholas V. Feodoroff, 1952
    - Margaret C. Ferguson, 1958 1963
    - Karl H. Fernow, 1930 1932 1940
  - Fer-Fle (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Dean H. Ferris, 1952
    - Eldred Fewkes, 1961
    - J.M. Fife, 1950
    - Keith W. Finlay, 1952-1954 1956-1958
    - George W. Fisher, 1956
    - P.L. Fishback, 1943
    - Simon Flexner, 1926 1929 1931 1935
  - Waldo R. Flinn, 1950-1951 1954-1956 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Flo-Fol (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - H.H. Flor, 1964
    - A.B. Flores, 1962
    - Emmanuel T. Floresca, 1961 1964
    - Florida, USDA, 1961
    - L.P. Flory, 1938
    - John E. Flynn, 1947
    - Edward Foley, 1941
    - Donald Folsom, 1942
  - Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Food and Agricultural Organization - (FAO) Bangkok, 1961
    - Food and Agricultural Organization - (FAO) Field Reports, 1961-1962
  - Food and Agricultural Organization - (FAO) Manila, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - FAO New Delhi - FAO Rome, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Food and Agricultural Organization - New Delhi, 1964
    - Food and Agricultural Organization - New York, 1962
    - Food and Agricultural Organization - Rome, 1960-1961
  - Food and Agricultural Organization - (FAO) Rome, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Food and Agricultural Organization - (FAO) Rome, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Food and Agricultural Organization - (FAO) Washington, 1956 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - For-Fos (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Richard E. Ford, 1960-1961
    - F.C. Forsbeck, 1930
    - H.C. Forster, 1953
    - C.M. Fortich, 1961
    - A. Alfred Foster, 1943-1944 1947
    - Harold H. Foster, 1940 1946 1950
    - R.C Foster
  - Fran-Fras (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Giuseppe Franchini, 1930-1931 1935
    - Thomas Francis, Jr., 1939 1949
    - Hans M. Franke, 1938
    - Rosalind Franklin, 1956
    - Dean Fraser, 1966
  - W.A. Frazier, 1945-1950 1952-1954 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Fre-Frie (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - J.B. Free, 1964-1966 1968
    - Monroe E. Freeman, 1936
    - Elinor B. Freitag, 1937
    - J.H. Freitag, 1945 1954
    - Y. Fremond, 1961
    - Alex M. French, 1950
    - W.F. Friedewald, 1945
    - Natalie Friedheim, 1962
    - Bernard A. Friedman, 1956 1958 1960
  - Frig-Fu (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Frigid, Inc., 1964
    - Juan G. Frivaldo, 1961
    - E.F. Frolik, 1949
    - Teikichi Fukushi, 1940 1958-1959
    - E.H. Fulling, 1957
    - R.H. Fulton, 1955
    - Robert W. Fulton, 1949 1953 1956-1957 1959-1960
    - Kwok Ying Fung, 1945 1947
  - Gad-Ganc (Box 8, Folder 5)